Bio

Joe Letchford is a graphic designer from Richmond, Virginia. He specializes in graphic design, web design, art direction, visual identity systems, publications, and various print media in the commercial and cultural sectors. Together with Josh Osborne, he runs the enthusiastic, non-geographic studio, Tiny Chime.

He believes strongly in experimentation and collaboration. His creative process endeavors to achieve meaning through dialogue and close partnerships within the specifications of each project.

Experience

June 2017 → Present / Washington, DC Design Army

Senior designer at Design Army focusing on branding, web design, and print. Primary web designer for the agency and 2+ additional clients. Regularly manage 8+ projects concurrently with strict deadlines. Delivered 8+ complete projects to agency clients since June 2017.

July 2015 → May 2017 / Minneapolis, MN MCAD DesignWorks

Graphic designer for the Minneapolis College of Art and Design in-house studio focusing on exhibition identity, branding, print, and publication design. Responsible for 12+ advertisements and publications for the college and 3 outside clients.

February 2015 → May 2015 / Richmond, VA RiggsWard

Freelance graphic designer for RiggsWard focused on web design, branding, and print media. Delivered the studio's internal identity redesign, front-end web redesign, and pre-production within 3 months.

February 2014 → January 2015 / Richmond, VA Epiphany Studio Graphic designer at Epiphany Studio.

May 2013 → August 2013 / Washington,` DC Fathom Creative
Graphic design intern for Fathom Creative.

Education

Minneapolis College of Art and Design Minneapolis, MN MFA in Visual Studies, 2017.

Virginia Commonwealth University Richmond, VA. BA in Anthropology, 2014.

Proficiencies

Branding, Identity, Web Design, Brand Development, Collateral Design, Print and Publication Design, Rapid Prototyping, HTML, CSS, Adobe Suite, Sketch, InVision.

References

Dylan Cole Studio Manager, MCAD DesignWorks dcole@mcad.edu 616.802.0614

Ryan Nelson Senior Designer, Walker Art Center ryangerald.nelson@gmail.com 612.867.2276 makingknown.org makingknown-flatfiles.tumblr.com

Josh Osborne Design Technologist, NPR josborne@npr.org 202.617.5228 josh.graphics